We always knew this day would come.
San Andreas is a action, drama, thriller film directed by Brad Peyton.
In the aftermath of a massive earthquake in California, a rescue-chopper pilot makes a
dangerous journey across the state in order to rescue his estranged daughter.
Ray Gaines, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Blake Gaines, played by Alexandra Daddario.
Emma Gaines, played by Carla Gugino.
Daniel Riddick, played by Ioan Gruffudd.
Serena Johnson, played by Archie Panjabi.
Dr. Lawrence Hayes, played by Paul Giamatti.
San Andreas is a 2015 American disaster thriller film starring Dwayne Johnson.
The film was directed by Brad Peyton and written by Carlton Cuse.
Carla Gugino, Alexandra Daddario, Ioan Gruffudd, Archie
Panjabi and Paul Giamatti also star.
Its plot centers on a massive earthquake caused by the San Andreas
Fault that devastates the West Coast of the United States.
Principal photography of the film started on April 22, 2014, in
Queensland, Australia, and wrapped up on July 28 in San Francisco.
The film premiered in Hollywood, Los Angeles, on May 26, 2015,
and was released in the United States on May 29.
It received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the visual effects and Johnson
and Gugino's performances but criticized the plot and characters.
The film grossed $475 million worldwide on a $110 million budget.
The film explores themes of california, san francisco,
california, looting, earthquake, tsunami.
The tone is emotional and intense.